到底过了多久...
How long have I...
头部外伤...
Forced trauma to the head...
那次事故后他持续昏迷...
since the accident,he'sabchad a continued...
- 为啥我不能动弹?abc- 无高血压病史...
- Why can't I get up?abc- No episodes of hyperten...
- 我的腿怎么了?abc- 心电图正常...
- What's wrong with my legs?abc- Ekg's show normal...
找个人理理我啊abc你们没有听到我说话吗?
Someone talk to me. Youabcdon't hear me talking to you?
感觉试验正常 肌钙蛋白正常...
Normal feelingabcpressure,normal C.K.Troponin...
他的心脏很适合器官移植
Great heart for transplant.
我的心脏? 天啊!abc他们不知道我还活着
My heart? Oh,god! Theyabcdon't know I'm in here.
等等 天才
Hey,genius.
我觉得摘了活人的器官违反人道主义哦
I think it violates certain ethical laws toabcrip the organs out of a guy who's still alive.
- 甚至可能违法abc- 真是太感谢你了
- Possibly certain law laws too.abc- Thank you. Thank you.
House先生 拜托 你能不能躺回床上?
Could you,um,get backinabcyour bed,please,mr. House?
其实我是House医生
It's actually doctor house.
这家伙竟然是医生?
This guy's a doctor?
还有海豹特种队房子
There's also navy seal house.
那可不容易见到
But you're going to have toabcsave up for that one.
是吗? 这挺好玩 不过...
Really? Well,that's interesting,but...
你之所以在这里 是因为你摩托翻车了abc不是因为我找你会诊
you're here because you crashed yourabcmotorcycle,not because I need a consult.
所以回到你的床上
So,get back in bed.
摔了肘部 我只需要一卡车维科丁abc可这家伙--
I scraped my elbow,I just need aabctruck load of vicodin.Whereas,this guy--
- 他脑死亡了abc- 我不是!
- He's brain dead.abc- No,I'm not!
- 所以放弃吧abc- 看到没?
- So drop it.abc- See that?
中脑波不能说明大脑还有活动
Minimal brain waves don't mean he's alive.
- 我还活着! 我在这!abc- 疼痛冷热刺激均无法引起心电图反应
- I am alive! I'm here!abc- No ekg response to painful stimuli,hot or cold.
你看到的只是随机的 难以辨别
What you're seeing isabcrandom,barely discernable.
- 可我看到了abc- 拜托听听他说
- I discerned it.abc- Listen to him,please.
那只是放大器的内部噪声线
No,that's just the amplifier'sabcinternal noise level.
- 敏感度增强了abc- 不是啊!是我
- It's on increased sensitivity.abc- No,it's not! It's me.
- 那为啥他的眼睛一直看着你啊?abc- 太对了
- Then why is his eye following you?abc- Exactly.
- 眼球运动只是非自主反应abc- 不是啊
- Following motion's an involuntary reflex.abc- No.
你是医生...abc这些事你应该懂的
You're a doctor... youabcshould know these things.
不要啊 我还活着abc帮帮我啊 我还没死!
No,no,I'm not dead,Iabcneed help. I'm here!
我还懂得闭锁综合症--
I also know aboutabclocked-in syndrome--
病人的反应若不是非自主的...abc就是自主的
that things are eitherabcinvoluntary... or voluntary.
- 如果你听到就眨眨眼abc- 我听到
- Blink if you can hear me.abc- I hear you.
这可好玩了
Oh,this is going to be fun.
闭眼是自主运动
Eye movement is deliberate.
你能眨眼一次表示"是"abc两次表示"不是"吗
Can you blink once forabc"yes," twice for "no?"
我尽量吧
I hope so.
9的平方根是几?
The square root of nine?
他答得比你快哦
He got that faster than you.
- 大脑非常正常abc- Lee...
- The brain is fully functional.abc- Lee...
Molly在哪?
Where's molly?
你出了车祸
You were in an accident.
刹车 刹车 刹车啊!
Hit the brake,hit theabcbrake,hit the brake!
外伤累及脑干
You've sustained a traumaticabcinjury to your brain stem
因此切断了大脑控制机体的通路
which has cut off your brain's abilityabcto communicate with the rest of your body.
你能治好我吗? Molly呢?
Can you fix me? Where's molly?
但眼球运动还存在
You still have movement in your eyes.
我们可以把你送到康复中心abc他们会教你如何与人沟通
So we can get you to a rehab facilityabcwhere they can teach you how to communicate.
不 我不能这样过一辈子
No,I can't be stuck like this.
除非...脑部损伤不是由车祸引起的
Unless... the crash didn'tabccause the brain damage.
可能是脑部损伤导致车祸
Maybe the brain damage caused the crash.
是啊 我刹不了车abc为什么我停不下来?
Yeah,I couldn't stop.abcWhy couldn't I stop?
看他的手掌 没有伤痕
Look at his palms. There's no scrapes.
他甚至没有自卫的动作
He didn't even try to protect himself.
所以你反应迟钝--或没有反应
So you had slowedabcreflexes-- or no reflexes.
你不会是这医院的医生abc你只是病人
You're not a doctor in thisabchospital. You are a patient.
你这家伙只想摘了我的器官abc可他没有
Yeah,and you're the guy who wants to cutabcout my organs,and he's the guy who doesn't.
中风 肿瘤或微小的感染abc只要累及脑桥 就会出现这种症状
Stroke,cancer,even a simple infection,anythingabcthat insults the central pons could do this.
这是不是意味着我有治愈的机会啊
Then that means that I could be fixed.
你只是给他空指望
You're giving him false hope.
他需要接受事实
He needs to accept what's happened.
然后学着改进
And work on making the most of it.
Molly
Molly.
别这样看着我abc这只会让我更难受
Don't look at me like that.abcThat's not making me feel better.
我爱你
I love you.
我不知道老天会如何渡我们过难关abc但他一定会帮我们的
I don't know how god is going toabcget us through this. But he will.
别说了 我都脸红了
Stop it. I'm blushing.
你在干啥?
What are you doing?
想找些东西在如厕时读读
Just looking for some readingabcmaterial for the crapper.
- 这些CT--abc- 回你的床 去吧
- These cts-- - Getabcback in your bed.Come on.
孩子们在候诊大厅abc我可以带他们进来?
The children are in the waitingabcarea,can I bring them in?
不 千万不要
No. No,don't.
你不想见到他们吗?
You don't want to see them?
我不想他们做噩梦abc我不要吓着他们 Molly
I don't want them having nightmares.abcI don't want to scare them,molly.
你不想他们看到你这样子 对吗?
You don't want them to see you?
没事 我理解
It's okay. I understand.
你很快就会好起来的
You're going to be better soon enough.
真的吗?
You really that sure?
你确定吗?abc亲爱的 为什么你这么肯定?
Why are you so sure?abcBaby,how'd you get so sure?
你没事吧?
You okay?
- 好得很呢abc- 这是你的汉堡包
- Never better.abc- Here's your burger.
如果没法让穆罕默德去Princeton医院abc就带Princeton的医生来治穆罕默德
If you can't bring mohammed toabcprinceton,bring princeton to mohammed.
这是我的医疗小分队
That's my diagnostics posse.
辣妹 黄种人 还有黑人
Hot,dark,and darker.
拜托说说怎么能治好我吧
Talk about getting me better,please.
- 你去米德尔顿干嘛?abc- 少管我
- What are you doing up in middletown?abc- Who cares?
去买57年造的Gibson金色吉他
Buying a gibson '57 goldtop.
那是Duane Allman用过的abc(allman brother's band的主奏吉他手)
It's the guitar duaneabcall man used to play.
除了外伤 引起突发性闭锁综合症的原因
Next to the trauma,the mostly likelyabccauses of a sudden onset of locked-in syndrome
莫过于基底动脉梗阻和脑出血
are basilar arteryabcstroke,and brain hemorrhage.
Ct正常
Ct was clean.
大哥 那些薯条看起来不错哦
Man,those fries look good.
他是个自行车运动爱好者abc心脏没问题
Guy's an active bikeabcrider,his heart's fine.
肿瘤可以解释
A well-placed tumor could explain .
天呐 我以后再不能吃东西了吗
Jeez,is the last thing I ateabcgonna be the last thing I ate?
CT可能无法显示abcMRI可以发现异常
It could evade the ct,and stillabcshow up on an mri with contrast.
最后吃的是一根融化了的能量棒
It was a melted power bar.
她挺聪明的
She's the smart one.
黄家伙和黑家伙是凑数的
I just keep dark and darkerabcto fill out the quota.
如果找到病因 对症治疗abc你会痊愈的
If we find it,treatabcit,you could be fine.
我以前从来不会祈求我得脑瘤abc但拜托 如我所愿吧
I never thought I'd be praying forabca brain tumor,but please,dear god.
如果你是在祈愿 立即停止
If you're praying inabcthere,stop it right now.
我们马上让医生安排MRI
We'll get his doctor to order an mri.
他的医生正忙着abc让他学用眨眼表达"杀了我"的摩斯码
His doctor's busy teaching him howabcto blink out "kill me" in morse code.
幸运的是我在床垫下找到些预约单
Luckily,I found someabcforms under the mattress.
看 他们有MRI视频护眼镜
Check it out,they haveabcthose mri video goggles.
- 我觉得这很炫abc- 你想到什么了?
- I heard these were awesome.abc- What do you see?
是沙滩
It's a beach.
看 Taub来了...
Oh,look,there's taub...
喝杯玛格丽特abc嘲笑我们跑那么远来这里
drinking a margarita and mocking usabcfor driving all the way up here...
轻点 我还活着
Easy,I can still feel in here.
我替Kutner医生说声抱歉abc他只是对新东西很兴奋罢了
Excuse dr. Kutner,he gets a littleabcexcited about new technology.
里面会有些吵 空间有点小
It can get loud in there,andabca little closed off.
护目镜让你进入安详的环境
These will put you in a quiet place.
你可以想象个放松的场景
You can create a relaxingabcscenario for yourself.
我希望... 哇
I hope they... wk.
你竟然在我的想象中?
You're in my relaxing scenario?
我以为你喜欢见到我
I guess you ike me.
也有可能你是派来的
Either that,or you got sent here.
什么? 上帝派我来的?
What? By god?
我也不知道我信不信上帝
I'm not sure if I believe in god.
你要不是信徒abc在教堂花的时间未免太多了
You spend an awful ot of time inabcchurch for someone who doesn't.
我也不是完全不信
I don't not believe either.
要么信 要么不信
It's either one or the other.
我去教堂只是想让我老婆开心 可...
I go to church mainly toabckeep my wife happy,but...
我不知道abc我从来不认为上帝会影响我的生活
I don't know,I've never actually thoughtabcthat god could reach out and affect my life.
可他竟然让医神睡在我邻床?
But getting a brilliantabcdoctor in the bed next to me?
在前方打开轿车车门的也是上帝
God is also the guy who openedabchis car door in front of you.
我想Molly是对的 你是为了治好我而来的
I think molly was right. I think youabcwere sent here to make me get better.
希望是吧
I think so.
嘿 老爸
Hey,dad.
来堆火山吧
Making a volcano.
你在堆火山? 很像哦 亲爱的 你在干啥呢?
You're making a volcano? It looksabclike it. What you doing,baby?
- 几点了?abc- 希望你不介意
- What time is it?abc- Hope you don't mind.
我的新邻床打鼾
My new roommate snores.
而且新病房里没有你
And my new room doesn't have you.
你的MRI显示脑桥损伤
Your mri showed aabclesion in the central pons.
那是啥? 是什么意思?
What is that? What does that mean?
- 看见那了吗?abc- 没有
- See it there?abc- No.
有些人也看不出 但损伤存在
Mm,that's what theyabcsaid. But it's there.
不是外伤造成的
Which means no way head trauma did this.
是肿瘤造成了瘤外综合征
It's cancer,causing aabcparaneoplastic syndrome.
然而你的主治医师认为abc这弥散分布的密度影是感染
Unfortunately,your current doctor thinksabcits diffuse nature means an infection.
坏消息是他使用的抗病毒药会杀了你
And the bad news is,the antiviralsabche's got you on might kill you.
我不想死
I'm not gonna die.
但好消息是abc它们只是差点杀死你
But the good news is ifabcthey just almost kill you,
接着白痴医生会发现abc他的名字并不是巧合
then dr. Idiot will realizeabcthat his name is not a coincidence
- 然后就会让我为所欲为了abc- 谢谢
- and he'll let me do whatever I want.abc- Thank you.
但讽刺的是...
See,the irony here is...
我觉得你很迷人
you're kind of fascinating.
我有很多疑问
So many questions.
假使你能开口回答 就不迷人了
But if y could answer any ofabcthem,yo wouldn't be fascinating.
我明白了 这人有点神经
I get it,you're a little nuts,aren't you?
你老婆会帮你渡过难关
Your wife is theabcone getting you through this.
你老婆还有我
Your wife and me.
但老实说 做个MRI比abc握住你的手四小时都管用
Although frankly,the mri was a lot moreabcuseful than four hours of hand-holding.
我想
I think.
如果你有个老婆abc就会明白这有多重要了
If you had a wife,you'dabcknow why it matters.
你是个好人 很容易沟通
You're a good guy. Easy to talk to.
慢着 有点不对劲abc我的身体怎么了?
Wait,something's happening.abcWhat's happening to me?
来人帮忙那!
I need some help in here!
你们的病人抽搐了
Your patient is seizing.
他为什么会抽搐?
Why would he have a seizure?
因为他有癌症!
Because he has cancer!
他的脑干受到了损伤
His brain stem is compromised.
干嘛和这人争辩?abc你以为我死了
Why are you still arguing withabcthis guy? You thought I was dead.
欢迎重返人间 做得好abc你差点死了 正如我们计划的
Welcome back. And nice played. Youabcalmost died. Exactly as we planned.
你知道会发生这种情况?
You knew this was going to happen?
当你不拿癌症当癌症治疗时abc就会发生这种状况
It usually happens when you treatabccancer by pretending it's not cancer.
对吧 医生? 轮到我了么?
Right,doctor? My turn?
- 是癌症吗?abc- 不 不是
- It's cancer?abc- No,it isn't.
是的!
Yes!
他脑干里有个小肿瘤abc引发了副肿瘤综合症
A small tumorin his brainabcstem,causing paraneoplastic syndrome.
他需要做血浆置换
He needs plasmapheresis.
你能帮他做吗?
Can you give that to him?
不 很抱歉 我完全不同意House医生
No,I'm sorry,Iabccompletely disagree with dr. House.
- 拜托给我闭嘴abc- 我同意
- Please shut up.abc- I don't.
就是说我能给他治疗
Which means I can treat him.
让他做吧 让他做吧
Let him. Let him.
- 你想做这个治疗吗?abc- 当然
- Is that what you want?abc- Absolutely.
你能不能给我找几个小工来?
Would you send up a couple of bellboys?
我拿到了转院文件 血浆置换也准备好了abc你没事吧?
I got the transfer papers. Plasmapheresisabcis all set up. Are you okay?
有点小伤更爷们 你喜欢不?
Fresh infusion of macho. You like?
我动都不会动了abc她只关心他那点小伤?
I can't move,and she'sabcworried about his boo-boo?
你到底去那里干什么?
What were you doing up there,anyway?
搜罗古董 我给你买了件维多利亚时代的胸衣abc待会过来我帮你束起来
Antiquing. I found you a te victorianabccorset. Come by later,I'll tie you up.
他喜欢她?
Is he hitting on her?
如果她掉头 说明她也有那意思abc他们俩...哦也
If she turns around,she'sabcinto him too. And ther yeah.
抱歉我先前没出现abc我没收到短信
Sorry I didn't show up inabcmiddletown. I didn't get the message.
大概因为根本没给你发
Probably because there was no message.
我决定接受你的辞职
I've decided to accept your resignation.
我以为我们已经说清楚了abc我决定留下
Uh,I thought we were pastabcthis. I decided to stay.
不 你只是接收了我的安排
No,you didn't. Youabchad it decided for you.
被迫留在知道你要跳槽的老板手下
So now you're stuck here with a boss whoabcknows that you want to be somewhere else.
也就是说 你不再努力让我对你刮目相看
Which means you're noabclonger motivated to impress me,
也就是说 你失去了想出好点子的动力
which means you're no longerabcmotivated to come up with good ideas.
除非我错了
Unless I'm wrong.
拯救拉拉队员 拯救你的世界abc(剧集"英雄"台词)
Save the cheer leader. Save your world.
下面的我来就好
I got it from here.
我以为你找到了病因abc你觉得你可能是错的?
I thought you already solved this.abcAre you thinkingyou might be wrong?
到底会怎样?
What's going on?
嘿 只是好奇...abc你开车去米德尔顿干嘛?
Hey,just curious... what wereabcyou driving up to middletown for?
- 你为什么在乎?abc- 他为什么在乎?
- What do you care?abc- Why does he care?
因为我是你的朋友
Because I'm your friend.
- 我去买把吉他abc- 没错 我听说了
- I was buying a guitar.abc- Yeah,I heard that.
你说那把吉它的前主人abc死于摩托车事故
It used to belong to a guitaristabcwho died in a motorcycle accident.
你随口冒出的都是谎话
It just reeks of youabcscrewing with people.
你发生车祸的地点距离abc橘郡疼痛专科医院只有10里路
Your crash was ten miles from theabcorange county progressive pain clinic.
你住的地方距离玛丽女装店只有10里路
You live ten miles fromabcmary's dress shop.
但我丝毫没有因此怀疑abc你暗地里喜欢男扮女装
And yet,that's not even on my list of reasonsabcthat I think you'resecretly a transvestite.
如果你想到别的州去开更多的止痛药--
If you're going to another stateabcto get more narcotics--
- 他在嗑药?abc- 我去拜访你的前前前妻...
- He's on drugs? - I went toabcvisit your ex-ex-ex-wife...
- 什么?abc- 她住汤普森镇
- What?abc- Who livesin thompson ridge.
我告诉她 你巡回演讲赚了不少外快
I let her know about the extra moneyabcyou're making on the lecture circuit.
她肯定会找你提高赡养费了
So she'll be sure to adjust your alimony.
- 你不会这么做的abc- 对 我不会这么做
- You wouldn't do that.abc- Yeah. I wouldn't do that.
你会吗?
Would you?
你们俩是朋友?
You guys are friends?
我们不是应该娱乐一下病人吗?
Shouldn't we be entertaining our patient?
我刚用布袋木偶演欧里庇得斯的剧目
I performed euripides with sock puppets.
你错过了
You just missed it.
House让我们这么做
House said we should.
思想和肌肉一样
The mind is like a muscle.
不锻炼就会萎缩 和所有东西一样
If you don't exercise it,it'llabcatrophy,just like anything else.
无论谁在他身边 都得和他说话
Whoever's with him needs to talk.
让他的思想保持活跃abc也向House证明 你在乎这份工作
Keep his mind active,and it'llabcshow house you still care.
我不肯定我是否在乎
Not sure if I do.
- 上帝 你可是我的医生abc- 那你为什么不干脆辞职?
- Jeez,you're my doctor?abc- Then why don't you just quit?
我也不确定我想这么做
I'm not sureI want to do that,either.
也许你应该在House替你找到答案前abc自己先找到答案
Maybe you should figure it outabcbefore house figures it out for you.
没错 也许你应该在我好转后abc才继续中年危机的苦恼
Yeah,maybe you should have yourabcmidlife crisis after I'm better.
Kutner...
- 我们马上回来abc- 等等
- We'll be right back.abc- Wait.
等等 你们看到什么了?
Wait,what did you just see?
- 你喝酒吗?abc- 他是修屋顶工
- Do you drink?abc- He's a roofer.
酒精无法证实你的理论
Alcohol hardly proves your theory.
原发性肼胝体变性符合症状
Marchiafava bignami disease fits.
肝功能测试正常
Lft's are normal.
拜托能不能说英语abc能治吗 这是什么意思?
Speak english. Is itabcfixable? What does that mean?
这样很痛
That hurts.
没有颤搐
No tremors.
你喝多少酒? 一天六罐?
How much do you drink?abcA six-pack a day?
- 我讨厌啤酒 我几乎没怎么喝过abc- 也许他多少喝过
- I hate beer,I don't even drink beer.abc- Maybe more or less.
也许是别的原因
Or maybe something else.
也许跟酒精无关
It may not be alcohol at all.
街头毒品也可能引起闭锁--
Street opiates canabcalso cause locked-in--
我不嗑药
I don't get high.
要么我们把2万种街头毒品全部问上一遍
So,eitherwe play 20,000abcquestions with every street drug,
要么我们跳过他 直接和损伤对话
or instead of talking toabchim,we talk to the lesion.
- 问我好了abc- 你要给他的脑干做活检?
- Talk to me.abc- We're goingto biopsy the brain stem?
这可不算是你的主意
For the record,that doesn't countabcas your inspired idea.
我本来正要得出这结论
It's sort of where I was heading.
你们要切开我的脑子? 为什么?
You're going to cut into my head? Why?
不要把我当一件家具摆弄!
Stop treating me likeabca piece of furniture!
我有权知道接下来会怎样!
I have a right to know what's going on!
这是干嘛的?
Where's that going?
尿液中的血堵塞了你原来的导尿管
Blood in your urine cloggedabcup your old catheter.
尿血? 那个朝不保夕的医生abc先前肯定是看到了这个
Peeing blood? That must beabcwhat the insecure doctor saw.
每个新的线索都会使我们更接近答案
Every new clue getsabcus closer to the answer.
- 靠abc- 手术会为我们提供新的线索
- Damnit.abc- The surgery will get us more clues.
有人来看望你
You have visitors.
不要 噢 Molly
No. Oh,molly.
进来吧
Come in.
- 爸爸!abc- 爸爸!
- Daddy!abc- Daddy!
我告诉过你 不要把他们带来
I told you not to bring them.
他们想见爸爸
Well,they wanted to see their father.
我甚至不能拥抱他们
I can't even hug them.
他们承受得来
They can handle it.
你会好起来的
It's going to be all right.
你没先前这么笃定了
You're not so sure anymore,are you?
他们一定告诉你 我的病情很危急
They must've toldabcyou that it's dangerous.
我可能会死
That I could die.
所以你把他们带来...
And that's why youabcbrought them in here...
我测验得了A+
I got an a+ on my test.
...来见我最后一面
To see me before I die.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you,daddy.
爸爸也爱你
Daddy loves you too.
我让你看看我画的画
I wantto show you my drawings.
孩子只想要一个爸爸
Kids just want a dad.
哪怕他已成了植物人
Even if he's just a lump.
也许你们应该离开了
Maybe you should go now.
噢 不 求你让他们留下
Oh,no. They canabcstay,please. Let them stay.
再见 爸爸
Bye,daddy.
对不起 你哭了
Sorry. You were crying.
靠
Damn.
我们要麻醉你 好在你脑袋上钻洞
We're going to put you out,justabcso we can drill the hole.
噢 你真是太贴心了
Oh,that's very thoughtful of you.
然后我们会让你醒来
Then we'll wake you back up.
我们切割时 会问你几个abc简单的"是或否"的问题
We'll need you to answer some simpleabcyes or no questions while we're cutting,
- 确保我们没有切...abc- 看来药物起效了
- to make sure we're not cutting...abc- It seems to be working.
深呼吸
Deep breaths.
10秒钟后 你会感到眩晕
In about ten seconds,you'llabcfeel lightheaded.
现在...
And by now...
你会感觉到你在天空中漂浮
you should be floatingabchigh with lucy in the sky.
如果我真好不了怎么办?
How come I'm not better?
上帝不会做错了推倒重来
God's not supposed toabcwork in trial and error.
上帝犯的错误 大大有案可稽
God's mistakes are well-documented.
如果上帝每次一开始就能把事情办对abc史上就只有一次瘟疫且没有大洪水了
If he'd done everything right the first time,there'dabchave been one plague and zero great floods.
那是因为人类犯错了
Those were because of human mistakes.
你以为你的医生住在奥林匹亚山上?
You think your doctor has anabcapartment on mount olympus?
上帝派你来是有原因的
God put me with you for a reason.
我还是会好起来的 对不对?
I'm gonna be all right still,right?
我不知道
I don't know.
Lee 听到我说话了吗?
Lee. You with me now?
很简单的问题 不费劲的
Easy questions. You'llabcbe done before you know it.
这个等式是正确的吗?
Is this equation correct?
怎么 就是说你一失手abc我就答不上这问题了?
What,so if you make a mistake,I'mabcnot going to know that anymore?
这些线条是平行的吗?abc空间关系感没有缺损
Are these lines parallel?abcSpatial relationships intact.
看看这个圆
Take a look at this circle.
阴影超过一半吗?
Is more than half of it shaded?
当然了
Of course.
不要忘了眨眼 这个圆超过一半有阴影吗?
Don't forget to blink. Is moreabcthan half of the circle shaded?
对不起 是的
Sorry,yes.
看着我 Lee 再问一次
Look at me,lee. Again.
这个圆超过一半有阴影吗?
Is more than half of this circle shaded?
- 眨眼 拜托 Lee 眨眼abc- Foreman 停下来
- Blink. Come on,lee,blink.abc- Foreman,back out.
为什么我不能眨眼?abc为什么不能眨眼了?
Whyan't I blink? Why can't I blink?
为什么他的眼球不会动了?
Why aren't his eyes moving?
两个可能: 我的神经科医师搞砸了
Two options: My neurologist screwed up,
或者当你公堂对簿时abc医院律师会编出别的理由
or else something the hospital lawyer'sabcgoing to have to come up with when you sue us.
眨眼和眼球转动均由abc很小的一束神经控制
Blinking and eye movements areabccontrolled by a small cluster of nerves,
离活检的地方只有几毫米
just millimeters from the biopsy site.
但他还有思想 对不对?abc只是无法交流了?
But he's still in there,right?abcI mean,he just can't communicate?
有可能
It's possible.
另一个可能是手术引起脑干肿胀abc他就这么去了
Also possible is that the surgery caused so muchabcswelling in his brain stem,that he's just gone.
他只有一种方法和我们交流abc现在也没了 做得好
He had one way to communicate,andabcnow that's gone. Well played.
脑活检显示有严重的髓鞘损伤abc问题是 为什么会这样?
Brain biopsy revealed severe damageabcto the myelin sheath. Question is,why?
EB病毒 微小核糖核酸病毒 疟疾
Epstein barr,picorna viruses,malaria.
他自己开店 和很多人来往abc可能由此染上了轮状病毒
He runs a business,meets a lot ofabcpeople,he could've picked up rotavirus.
病历里说他得过腹泻吗?
Did he report having bloody diarrhea?
他的妻子不确定 说他没提起过
The wife's not sure,saysabche doesn't complain.
你问他了吗?
Did you ask him?
我们得分轻重缓急 他病得只能眨眼了abc而追查病史得花上几个星期
We've prioritized. He can only blink,aabcreal history would've taken weeks.
如果他有EB病毒 他会肚子痛
If he had epste barr,he'dabchave belly pains.
如果他有微小核糖核酸病毒abc他会头痛
If he had picornaabcvirus,he'd have headaches.
只要再问五个"是或否"abc就能知道什么治疗方法能救他
Five other yes/no questions,andabcmaybe we'd know what treatment to give.
或者什么方法会杀死他
And what treatment would kill him.
除非他已经死了
Unless he's already dead.
也许还有别的办法
Maybe there's another way.
脑机接口-- 通常被称作BCI
Brain computer interface--abcbetter known as bci.
电子信号可以让你用思想控制指针活动
The go is to get you to moveabcthat cursor with your mind.
当你想着"向上"abc电脑会纪录你思维活动模式
When you think "up," theabccomputer records the pattern.
只要多想几次"向上"abc它就会捕捉到你思考的方式
Think "up" enough times,itabceventually learns what you're thinking.
那么...开始想"向上"吧
So... start thinking "up."
你还在吗?
You in there?
你在试着想吗?
Are you trying?
我给我前前前妻打了电话
I called theabcex-ex-ex-wife.
她上周去了新墨西哥州的蒸汗屋abc(印第安土法桑拿)
She was at a sweat lodge inabcnew mexico last week.
你到底去纽约干什么?
What were you really doing in new york?
你还真是烦我掺和你的谎言(lie)?
You know how you hateabcit when I meddle in your lies?
我指你的生活(life)
I mean your life.
为什么要扯开话题?
Why are you being so evasive?
除非你要逃避什么
Unless you have something to evade.
有意思
Interesting.
这事和你 你的前妻abc我的腿痛 完全没关系
This has nothing to do withabcyou,your ex-wife,or my pain.
我去了Fishkill镇的下城劳教所
I was heading to the down-stateabccorrectional facility in fishkill.
你相好的妓女约你去探监?
One of your hookers arrangeabca conjugal visit?
Foreman的弟弟关在那里
It's where foreman'sabcbrother is being held.
看来我得花上几个月的不眠之夜
This is going to mean monthsabcof sleepless nights,
思考原本我能改变些什么
wondering if I could've doneabcsomething differently.
也许我不是受不了House
Maybe it's not that I'm sick of house.
而是受不了每天...
It's that I'm sick of beingabcscared out of my mind
心惊胆颤地来上班
to go to work every day.
对不起
Sorry.
刚才是不是...
Did that just...
是你吗?
was that you?
你真的还在吗?
Are you really in there?
我知道你在
I knew you were in there.
- 我吓坏了abc- 感谢上帝
- I was scared.abc- Tha god.
现在还是很怕
I am scared.
Molly 我如此地爱你
Molly,I love you so much.
过去两星期你有没有腹泻带血?
Have you had any bloody diarrheaabcin the last two weeks?
排除轮状病毒
Rotavirus out.
有没有关节痛?
Any recent joint pain
排除EB病毒
Epstein barr's out.
最近有没有出国旅行?
Have you traveled outabcof the country lately?
国内旅行呢?
What about inside the country?
他去了圣路易斯(位于密苏里州)
He was in st. Louis.
好极 可能是密苏里疟疾abc我们开始治疗吧
Good. Could be missouriabcmalaria. Let's start treatment.
他的确-- 去了那里
He was--heabcwas there.
机器可能出问题了
The machine must not be working.
不然就是他骗你abc人们有时会这么做
Either that,or he lied to youabcabout it. People do that sometimes.
比如 我刚才骗他得了密苏里疟疾
For example,I just lied toabchim about missouri malaria.
你去了圣路易斯吗?
Did you go to st. Louis?
我当时应该告诉你abc我为什么不说实话呢?
I should've told you. Whyabcdidn't I just tell you?
向下
Down.
那两天既然你没去圣路易斯
When you weren't inabcst.Louis for two days,
我猜你去偷了两天的情
I assume you were getting someabcstrange for two days.
我妻子也这么想abc你得帮忙告诉她 我没有
So does she. You haveabcto tell her I wasn't.
厉害
Amazing.
一个只能控制两点光标的男人abc还是能够撒谎
A man who only has two blipsabcat his disposal can still lie.
我没有说谎
I'm not lying.
如果对象来路不是那么正经
If you were getting someabcreally strange strange,
你可能因此感染神经病毒abc侵入你的大脑 让你动弹不得
you could've contracted neu infectionabcwent to your brain,froze you right up.
好消息是 这是可治愈的
Good news is it's treatable.
你很快可以坐起身 签署你的离婚文件
You'll be up and moving in timeabcto sign the divorce papers.
既然我告诉你我没去圣路易斯abc我为什么要隐瞒这个?
Why would I tell you the truth about being in st.abcLouis,and then not tell you the truth about this?
他当着妻子面承认abc他没有去圣路易斯
He just admitted he wasn'tabcin st.Louis in front of his wife,
现在他妻子不在abc你认为他在撒谎?
and you think he's lying whenabcshe's not even in here?
我越来越喜欢这家伙了abc千万不要开除他
I'm liking this one moreabcand more. Don't fire him.
你是否离开了这个州?
Were you out of the state?
从来没有
I never left.
你在你家20里范围内吗?
Were you within 20 miles of your house?
是的
Yes.
- 5里之内?abc- 是的
- Were you within five miles?abc- Yes.
- 2里之内?abc- 是的
- Within two miles?abc- Yes.
- 你住在酒店里?abc- 不是
- Did you stay at a hotel?abc- No.
你总得有地方睡觉 在你车上?
You had to sleep somewhere. Your car?
不
No.
朋友家里?
A friend's house?
是的 是的
Yes. Yes.
范围缩窄了 接下来就取决于abc你有多受欢迎了
That narrows it down,dependingabcon how popular you are.
让他老婆别忙着哭 进来一下
Tell the wife to stopabccrying,get in here.
他说他之前说去圣路易斯abc其实是去了朋友家
He says that when he was supposed to be inabcst. Louis,he was staying at a friend's house.
- 是吗?abc- 是的
- Really.abc- Yes.
现在我们姑且相信他的说的是实话
Let's assume that youabcbelieve him for the moment.
- 说出你们住在2里内朋友的名字abc- Martin和Kim家?
- Name your friends within two miles.abc- Martin and kim's?
不
No.
说一个没有老婆的
Guess someone who doesn't have a wife.
- Dave?abc- 是的
- Dave?abc- Yes.
有地址吗?
Got an address?
如果他在这里染病abc别人应该也会出现症状
If this is where he got sick,someoneabcelse here should have symptoms.
如果Lee是唯一一个abc到过地下室的就不会
Not if lee was the onlyabcone coming down to the basement.
壁炉生锈了 但没有气体泄漏
Furnace is rusty,but no gas leaks.
这儿有些简历和求职信...
Resumes and cover letters here...
有的是几星期前写的
some are weeks old.
他来这儿已经好一段日子了
He's been spending time here for a while.
店里的生意不太好
Business wasn't going good.
我不想你和孩子担心
I didn't want you and the kids to worry.
我想保护你们
I was trying to protect you.
Molly...
我多希望你能听得到
I wish you could hear me.
我多希望这一切能好起来
I wish I could make all of this better.
看来他做了几次临时工 当清洁工
Looks like he temped aabcfew times. As a janitor.
在10号公路旁的一家工厂里
Factory out on route 10.
工厂工头说 他们生产充电电池
Factory foreman says they makeabcrechargeable batteries.
大部分供手机使用
Mostly for cell phones.
从自己开店到替人打扫abc简直天壤之别
Big step down from running yourabcown business,to sweeping up.
我只是尽力而为
Doing what I had to do.
金属锉末
Metal filings.
从颜色判断 我想是镉
Judging by the color,I'd say cadmium.
扫帚把锉末扬起来 被他吸入了肺部
Which he'd aerosolize with theabcbroom,then right into his lungs.
重金属中毒-- 解释了一切
Heavy metalabcpoisoning--explains everything.
螯合治疗可以清除你血液里的金属
The chelation will scrubabcthe heavy metals out of your blood.
如果我们找对了病因abc一天左右就会看到变化
If we are right about the cause,we shouldabcsee some movement in about a day or so.
不能快一点吗?
Can't put this thing on turbo?
我开始有点焦躁了
I'm gettinga little anxious in here.
这儿一直会有人守着abc给你滴眼药水
Somebody will be here at allabctimes to,uh,irrigate our eyes,
陪你说话
keep you company.
希望会让你觉得时间过得快一点
Hopefully,it'll helpabcmake the time go quicr.
我眼睛还是很干
My eyes still feel really dry.
谢谢...你想着"向上"
Thank you... for thinking "up."
让我知道你还在
For helping me find you in there.
伙计 当你移动那个箭头时...
Man,when you moved that cursor...
我给初恋女友买了根项链 是银制的
Bought my first girlfriend aabcnecklace. It was silver.
花了180美元-- 我攒了6个月
It cost 180 bucks--hadabcto save for six months.
她不喜欢
She hated it.
真的吗?
Really,seriously?
听你讲这故事 让人不耐烦呢
Did you tell this story toabcsomeone who could walk away?
从此我再也没给女友买过首饰
Never bought another girlfriendabcjewelry again.
- 直至Hadley医生abc- 你在和她约会?
- Until dr. Hadley.abc- You're dating her?
你每个故事都应该这么开头
You might want to start allabcyour stories with that.
结果还是一样...她根本没有戴
Same thing... she didn't even wear it.
你说那根钻石链子? 她前些天戴上了
The diamond thing,she wasabcwearing it the other day.
如果她不喜欢...她的确不喜欢
If she doesn't likeabcit,she doesn't like it.
显然 我选首饰的眼光很烂abc但她至少得老实告诉我
Apparently,I suckat picking outabcjewelry,but least have the guts to tell me.
好了 话题又变得沉闷了
Okay,getting boring again.
要多久才知道治疗有没有效?
How long until we know ifabcthis treatment is working?
你骗了我
You lied to me.
我没有外遇
I wasn't having an affair.
我们需要钱没错 谁在乎这个?
So we needed money. Who cares?
上一次生意不好时abc你每天都会偏头痛
Last time business was slow,youabcgot migraines every day.
你为什么这样对我?
Why would you do that to me?
对不起 我-- 我是傻子abc我-- 别 别走!
I'm sorry,I was--I wasabcstupid. I was--don't go! Don't!
靠 有谁能...替我把abc"对不起"打到这台白痴电脑上
Damn it,somebody... put "I'mabcsorry"on this stupid computer.
我的眼睛痛死了
My eye is killing me.
我想继续在这工作
I want to keep my job.
好啊 你只要想出一个好点子就成
Great. All you got to do isabccome up with a good idea.
我建议把病人的脑子接上电脑abc让他可以与人交流的点子如何?
How about we hook the guy's brainabcinto a computer,so he can communicate?
这是个好点子
That's a great idea.
对于那个发明了读心术电脑的家伙来说
For the guy who inventedabcthe computer that can read minds.
你的点子只是运用他的点子
Your idea was to use his idea.
但你没想到 别人也没想到
You didn't come up with it.abcNo one else came up with it.
如果不是我重建交流渠道abc我们就无法发现--
If I didn'tre-establishabccommunication,we never would've found--
有意思的是abc为什么你现在才来争取?
What's interesting isabcwhy you're here now.
而不是我给你下最后通牒时
Not when I gave you the ultimatum.
是不是病人说了什么?
Was it something the patient said?
我意识到 这里发生的一切...abc使我感到恐惧
I realized that what weabcdo here... terrifies me.
而且...
And...
克服这种恐惧abc我才能做个有用的人
overcoming that is theabconly way I can matter.
Kutner发现了电池厂的线索
Kutner found the battery factory.
Kutner想到是镉
Kutner came up with the cadmium.
也许你压根儿不重要
Maybe you don't matter.
我替你合上眼睛 好让你睡会儿
I'm going to close yourabceyes so you can get some sleep.
希望当你醒来时 病情会有所好转
Hopefully,when you wakeabcup,we'll see some improvement.
希望我的眼睛也会感觉好些
Hope that includes my eye feeling better.
把角膜染色荧光素钠递给我
Hand me the flourescein stain.
这是什么意思?
What's that mean?
上皮有点开裂
Epithelium looks torn.
这药水会有点刺
These drops sting.
我替你合上左眼保护它
I'm going to close your leftabceye to keep it protected.
我替你眨几下眼 让染色剂分布均匀
I'm going to blink your eye aabcfew times to distribute the dye.
溃疡性角膜炎
Ulcerative keratitis.
就是说不是镉中毒
Means it's not cadmium poisoning.
就是说你们不知道出了什么问题abc又一次
Which means you don'tabcknow what's wrong. Again.
你上次换衣服是什么时候?
When's the last time youabcchanged that dressing?
从这股味道判断 你从来没换过
Judging by the smellabcof it,I'd say never.
他有闭锁综合症 肾脏快炸裂了
He's locked-in,his kidneys blew a fuse,
现在眼睛还渗出脓来
and now his eye is oozing puss.
我猜你和你的小组abc已经探讨过这些问题了
I assume you went over allabcof that with your team.
看来他们没提出什么好点子abc否则你不会在这喃喃自语
I also assume they didn't have any brilliantabcideas,or you wouldn't still be muttering to yourself.
这会很痛
This is going to hurt.
他开始流失髓磷脂abc感染最为符合 可能是水痘--
The way he's losing his myelin makes anabcinfection most likely.Could be varicella--
石子碎片出来了 我得把它们刮掉
Road debris has come to the surface.abcI'm going to have to scrub it out.
但一开始无环岛苷就会把它治好了
But the initialabcacyclovir would've treated that.
那只能考虑自体免疫疾病了
Which pushes me towardsabcan autoimmune disease.
比如说 贝切特氏综合征
Like behcet'S.
这下会更痛 先吃两颗abc还有两颗留着待会吃
Here... this is going to hurtabceven more. Take two now,two later.
喔
Oops.
当然 如果水痘抗药性强abc那在米德尔顿做的治疗也起不了作用
Of course,if the varicella was resistant,itabcwouldn't matter what they did up in middletown.
做个脊髓穿刺
Do an lp.
看来你在急诊室呆得太久了
You've been in the er too long.
只要病人有头部创伤 白血球升高abc也能让你得出头部创伤的结论
When the patient had head trauma,white bloodabccells only indicate that he had head trauma.
或者你可以利用脊髓穿刺abc发现更有用的结果
Or you could use theabclp for something useful.
如果发现多中性粒细胞 就是水痘abc淋巴细胞 就是贝切特氏综合征
If you find polys,it'sabcvaricella. Lymphs,behcet'S.
我为什么开除你来着?
Why did I fire you again?
你没有 我辞职了
You didn't. I quit.
你也不是去探望Foreman的哥哥
You weren't visiting foreman'sabcbrother,either.
忙着呢...
Busy...
Kutner在做脊髓穿刺abc所以我要集中精神
kutner's doing an lp,so I have to focus.
我让监狱警卫查了探访记录 电话记录
I had prison securityabccheck visitor logs,phone records.
你没有接触过在Fishkill的任何人
You've never had anyabccontact with anyone at fishkill.
我再问一次...
So,I ask again...
你去米德尔顿干什么?
what were you doing up in middletown?
你知道比我做的事abc更有趣的是什么吗?
You know what's more interestingabcthan what I was doing?
是你为什么要纠结我在干什么
The reason you are soabcobsessed with what I was doing.
- 不要转移话题 Houseabc- 转移话题的是你
- Stop deflecting,house.abc- Says the deflector.
我去那里的目的...
The reason I was up there...
正是你害怕我去的原因
is the reason you'reabcscared I was up there.
我在追查你肮脏的小秘密
I was checking out yourabcdirty,little secret.
你和她上床多久了?
How long have you been sleeping with her?
你怎么知道?
How did you know?
你唯一的秘密便是某个使你难为情的女孩
Your only secrets are theabcgis you find embarrassing.
你最近遇到 唯一令你难为情的女孩abc在关你弟弟的疯人院里工作
And the only embarrassing girl you've met recentlyabcis the one at your brother's cuckoo facility.
我们就约会过几次
We've only been out a few times.
就像你其他前任一样 她也照顾人
She's a care giver. Like allabcof your other failed exes.
一个照顾你弟弟的人
And someone who takesabccare of your brother.
之前照顾你弟弟的是谁?
Who was the last person whoabctook care of your brother?
你认为这是恋母情结?
You think this is oedipal?
实际上 我在想的是自淫
Actually,I was thinking masturbatory.
我猜你妈妈是最先照顾他的人
I guess your mom took care of him first.
所以 最安全的措施是把你的眼睛挖出来
So,the safe course isabcto gouge your eyes out.
LP代表腰椎刺穿
Lp stands for lumbar puncture.
我们用这根针从你的脊椎里抽出骨髓
We use this needle tocollectabcfluid from your spine.
这针头真大
That's a really big needle.
你会觉得背上有极大的压迫感
You're going to feel some extremeabcpressure in your back.
我已经觉得前胸有压迫感了abc胸口好痛
I already feel pressure inabcmy front-- my chest hurts.
有些不对劲 不! 胸口!
Something's wrong. No,my chest!
感觉不对劲 我觉得我... 喔 上帝啊!
Something's wrong. Iabcthink I'm hav-- oh,god!
急救
Call the code.
这个世界上没有上帝
There is no god.
你不知道我得了什么病
You don't know what's wrong with me
看起来不是这样的
It doesn't seem that way.
那么说我死了?
So am I dead?
还没有
Not yet.
但你可能会死
But you're about to be.
好吧
Okay.
充电... 让开
Charging... clear.
再来... 让开
Again... clear.
救回来了
He's back.
不 不 让我死
No. No. Let me go.
他没办法治好我
He can't fix me.
我在这里已经三天了 哪都在疼
I've been here for threeabcdays,everything hurts.
算了 就这样吧
It's okay,just--justabcstop fighting.
她的生活会继续
She's got to go on with her life.
孩子不该面对这样的状况abc我不能为他们做什么 我不能
The kids don't need this.I can'tabcdo nothing for them--I can't--
挠一挠这只脚 真的真的很痒
scratch this foot--wow,thatabcreally,really itches.
- 置入一个心脏暂时起搏器abc- 闭嘴 闭嘴
- So we put ina temporary pacer.abc- Shut up,shut up.
他在试着说话
He's trying to talk.
有事困挠你吗?
Is something bothering you?
要是你觉得胸口紧的话abc这是意料之中的
If there's still tightness inabcyour chest,it's expected.
是眼睛吗?
Is it your eye?
他为什么要说三次"不"?abc你只问了一个问题
Why is he saying "no"three times?abcYou only asked one question.
也许他不是在说"不" 他是在说"向下"
Maybe he's not saying "no,"abcmaybe he's saying "down."
你是不是在说疼痛在更低的位置?abc多低? 是腿吗?
Are you saying that the painabcis lower? How low,your leg?
脚?
Your foot?
左脚?
Left foot?
检查一下他的 让我想想...abc他的右脚
Check his--let me seeabcnow-- yeah,his right foot.
没有瘀痕 没有皮疹 没有割伤
No bruises,no rashes,no cuts.
那么应该不会痛才对
Then there should beno pain.
有没有麻刺感?
Is there a tingling sensation?
是不是觉得痒?
Is it itching?
感到脚痒意味着肝功能衰竭
Itchy foot means liver failure.
肝脏没有问题 他体内的生化酶abc从我们接收他开始就是正常的
The liver's fine. His enzymes haveabcbeen normal since we admitted him.
我说的是"衰竭了" 而不是"正在衰竭"abc正如你一样
I didn't say "failing,"Iabcsaid "failure." Just like you.
肝脏就像是水上巡航舰
Liver's like a cruiseabcship taking on water.
当它开始下沉时 它发出求救信号
As it starts to sink,itabcsends out an S.O.S.,
只不过不同于电波 肝脏用的是酶
Only instead of radioabcwaves,it uses enzymes.
血液中含酶量越大 肝脏的情况越糟糕
The more enzymes in theabcblood,the worse the liver is.
当船沉没了之后 就没有求救信号了
And once the ship hasabcsunk,there's no more S.O.S.
你以为肝脏是好的 但实际上早就无可救药了
You think the liver's fine,but it'sabcalready at the bottom of the sea.
那么就是说衰竭的肝脏释放出毒素abc毒素损坏了神经 导致了闭锁综合症
So dying liver released toxins,damagedabcthe nerves,led to locked-in syndrome.
现在我们只需要知道是什么导致了肝衰竭
Now we just need to knowabcwhat's causing the liver failure.
肝脏 加上眼睛 还有肾脏abc很可能是硬化性胆管炎
Liver,plus eye,plus kidney--abcmost likely sclerosing cholangitis.
天哪 如果是Taub说出来的话abc就会是圆满的结局了
Oh,god,if only taub had said that,itabcwould've been a happy ending.
去做个活体切片确认
Do a biopsy to confirm.
我现在要麻醉待会做切片的部位
I'm going to numb up the area whereabcwe'll go in for the punch biopsy.
新手镯去哪了?
Where's the new bracelet?
她戴手镯了?
She was wearing the bracelet?
你之前没注意到我戴着吗?
You didn't notice that I was wearing it?
因为你没戴
Because you weren't.
他注意到了 但是你没有?
He noticed,and you didn't?
如果你不喜欢 没关系 这不是什么大问题
If you don't like it,it'sabcfine,it's not a big deal.
我喜欢 这才是重点
I like it,that's the point.
我宁愿把它放在家中的珠宝盒里abc也比在这儿被尿湿的好
I'd rather have itat home in theabcjewelry box than getting peed on at work.
你那只手臂上沾到过病人的尿样?
You got the patient's urine on that arm?
我插导尿管的时候 有什么问题吗?
When I was putting in the catheter. Why?
你起皮疹了
You've got a rash.
- 手镯是真的abc- 这我想到了
- The bracelet's real.abc- I figured.
那么如果皮疹不只是皮疹呢?
So what if the rash isn't just a rash?
如果这是一种感染呢?
What if it's an infection?
如果那地下室里有耗子的话abc肝衰竭可能是由于钩端螺旋体病引起的
If there were rats in that basement,then theabcliver failure could be caused by leptospirosis.
钩端螺旋体病通过尿液传播abc耗子传给他 他传给你
It transfers through urine.abcRat pee to him,his pee to you.
感染需要一个进入点
The infection would need an entry point.
检查一下有没有新的抓伤或者割伤
Look for any recent scratches,cuts.
看 在他指甲旁边
Look. Next to his fingernail.
感染损坏了你的肝脏abc释放的毒素引起了闭锁综合症
The infection destroyed your liver,which releasedabctoxins that caused the locked-in syndrome.
你差点因为被纸割伤而死掉
You were dying of a paper cut.
但愿你这次是对的
I hope you're right this time.
我们在你哥们Dave的地下室里找到了老鼠
We found rats in yourabcbuddy dave's basement.
测试证明了是钩端螺旋体病
Tested positive for leptospirosis.
这意味着现在的治疗是正确的
That means we're on the right treatment.
那么... 试着动动你的手指
So... try moving a finger.
你的大脑需要再次习惯工作abc再努力试一试
Your brain needs to get used toabcdoing its job again. Try harder.
我知道你已经放弃了希望
I'm sure you've lost hope.
我们曾告诉过你好多次说知道是什么病了abc但这次真的找对了
I know we've told you several times that weabcknew what this was,but this time we're right.
集中精神 为我试着去动动手指
Concentrate. Move one finger for me.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我成功了
I did it.
老鼠撒尿 这真是个好点子
Rat pee. Very nice idea.
是谁想出来的?
Who came up with it?
是我
I did.
很好
Good.
你对他抢功劳没有异议?
You okay with him claiming the credit?
是他想到的 他看到了皮疹...
It was his idea.Heabcsaw the rash--
如果真的是他 他会在我办公室外面abc挂上"任务完成"的横幅
If he did,he'd have hung a "missionabcaccomplished" banner in my outer office.
别耍他了 如果你打算解雇他...
Don't toy with him.Ifabcyou're going to fire him--
实际上 他偷了你的点子证明了abc他不惜撒谎 也要保住工作
The fact that he stole your ideaabcmeans that he cares enoughto lie.
这是我需要知道的 老鼠撒尿
That's all I needed to know. Rat pee.
真想得不赖
That's a very nice idea.
House 你把这留在我办公室了
House. You left this in my office.
不 我没有
No,I didn't.
我的口袋也没有漏
So either I have aabchole in my pocket--
喔 我现在想起来了 是我偷的
Oh,that's right Iabcremember now,I stole it.
因为如果你去了那 查我的女朋友
Because if you had gone upabcthere to check out my girlfriend,
你不会回来还就此向我撒谎
you wouldn't have come backabchere and lied to me about it.
你早就当着我的面神气活现了
You would've thrown her right in my face.
你低估了 让你钻牛角尖带给我的愉悦享受
You underestimate the entertainmentabcvalue of your obsessions.
在加上那些你当着我面不接的电话
And then there were all those callsabcyou weren't taking in front of me.
所以我打了那个你没接的号码
So I dialed the number ofabcthe calls you weren't taking.
你在看精神科医生
You're seeing a psychiatrist.
你没有权利侵犯我的隐私
You had no right to invade my privacy.
- 这...这是不是?abc- 对 这很讽刺
- Is--is that...?abc- Yeah. It's irony.
上帝把你派来的
god sent you.
突然之间 你没有那么令人着迷了
Suddenly,you're not so fascinating.
你在监视你的团队
You're spying on your team.
分一下轻重缓急 Wilson
Prioritize,wilson.
这是你现在真正想要拷问我的事吗?
Is that what you really want toabctorture me about right now?
我根本不想折磨你 我认为这很好
I don't want to torture you atabcall. I think this is a great thing.
你没必要花费一个小时车程abc神神秘秘地求医
Not something you have to drive anabchour out of town to shroud in mystery.
躺在别人的沙发上发牢骚abc真是没有虚掷光阴
Whining on someone's couch.abcThat's an excellent use of my time.
也许我会发现我的童年并不完美
Maybe I'll discover that myabcchildhood wasn't perfect.
所以 你对心理治疗的态度一点没变abc但是你还是去了
So your attitude about therapy clearlyabchasn't changed. And yet you went.
这让我觉得也许是别的事情变了
Which leads me to believe thatabcmaybe something else has changed.
也许你认为你能改变
Maybe you think you can change.
是Cuddy让你燃起希望
I credit cuddy with that.
不用归功于谁 因为我不会再去
Not much credit toabctake,because I'm not going back.
House 别...
Oh,house,please...
我假设你去那儿是因为abc你不愿意每次都亲手毁坏
I assume you went because you'reabctired of screwing up every chance..
- 得到幸福的可能abc- 最近联系人 删除联系人
- you get at happiness.abc- New contact. Delete contact.
不要因为我发现了事实而...
Do not let the fact thatabcI found out about it--
别责怪自己了 我不回去是因为这没用
Don't beat yourself up. I'm notabcgoing back because it doesn't work.
你会孤独无依
You'll end up alone.